Guide to the William J. Anderson photographs and papers, 1920s, 1947-2011, bulk 1960-2008 RL.11022
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Papers, 1947-2009 and undated
  Among the items of interest in the papers is a photocopy of a letter of thanks from Coretta Scott King dated 1983 and a response from Anderson, whose artwork was exhibited as part of the commemoration of King's 54th birthday.
  - Biographical, 1984-2005 and undated (Box 9)
  - General, 1947-1997 (Box 9)
    The earliest dated piece in the collection (1947) is a poem addressed to "W.J.," written by a teacher and extolling the young man's talents.
  - Sketchbook, circa 1957 (Box 9)
    The inside cover bears the inscription, "Layton School of Art," a progressive private school in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, where Anderson received his BA in Fine Art. Anderson's name is inscribed on the inside back cover. About 51 out of approximately 100 pages are filled with sketches of the human form and a few lecture notes; the rest are blank. There are no other known materials in the collection referring to this early period in Wisconsin.
  - General, 2000-2009 and undated (Box 9)
  - Correspondence and other items from Woubishet Kebede (Ethiopia), 1985-1995 (Box 9)
    A letter and a card from an arts teacher in Ethiopia, asking William Anderson for sponsorship to come to the U.S. to pursue advanced art studies. Documents he included with his correspondence to Anderson include a letter of recommendation, transcript, diploma, and his photograph.